A Guide to the Robert G. Blaylock Papers, 1953-2002
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Robert G. Blaylock Papers, 1953-2002
The Library of Virginia
42675
1.825 cubic feet (5 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Edith Miller Blaylock, Chapel Hill, North Carolina.
Biographical Information
Robert Glenn Blaylock was born in Guilford County, North Carolina on 16 April 1910. He was the son of William Henry Blaylock (1867-1950) and Bessie Elmina White (1874-1968). He attended North Carolina State College and Oak Ridge Military Academy (1931), and later graduated from the University of Maryland (1952). Blaylock was a superintendent of a furniture plant in Thomasville, North Carolina, and then owned and operated a trucking company. He married Jessie Maxine Moore (1910-1992) in 1935. Blaylock was commissioned a second lieutenant in the U.S. Army. He landed on Omaha Beach, and served throughout the duration of World War II. He was also a commander of an ordinate maintenance and supply battalion during the Korean War, and later commanded the Ordnance Technical Intelligent Agency in Arlington, Virginia. Blaylock retired from the military in 1962 with the rank of colonel. Afterwards, he joined the Foreign Science (Intelligence) and Technology Center in Washington, and served for 13 years. In 1965, he purchased a cattle farm in Wintergreen, Virginia, and bred Charolais cattle, and also worked in real estate. In 1989, he retired, and moved to Chapel Hill, North Carolina. Blaylock married Edith Miller in 1993. He was a lifetime member of the Friends Meeting of Gulford College. Robert Glenn Blaylock died in Chapel Hill on 17 April 2002.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1953-2002, of Robert G. Blaylock (1910-2002) of Chapel Hill, North Carolina, including genealogical research files on the Blaylock family of Halifax County, Virginia, and North Carolina, and the allied families of Blair, Kersey, Morgan, and White. The research was begun by Blaylock's brother, Frederick Royster Blaylock (1895-1953), who compiled "The Blaylock Family: A Summary Concerning Some of the Descendants of Martin Blaylock (1793-1871)." The collection includes abstracts and copies from Bible records, census records, deed books, military records, tombstone inscriptions, vital statistics, will books, as well as family group sheets, genealogical and pedigree charts, and research and printed genealogies by other individuals. Also included are obituaries, photographs, a Blaylock genealogy newsletter (1986-1990), and genealogical journals.
Contents List
- "The Blaylock Family: A Summary Concerning Some of the Descendants of Martin Blaylock (1793-1871)". (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "The Blaylock Family: A Summary Concerning Some of the Descendants of Martin Blaylock (1793-1871)" - Master Copy. (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Blaylock Family Research by Mrs. John F. McCurley. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Blaylock Genealogy Newsletter, 1986-1990. (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- "Blaylock Military Records" - Compiled by Colleen Blaylock Green, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Blaylock, Robert G. - Biographical Information. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Blaylock, Robert G. - Research Done in England and Scotland, 1957-1962. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Blaylock, Susan Fanny Cochran. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cemetery Records. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- D.A.R. - General Information. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Genealogical Groups. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "The Genealogical Journal" - Davidson County, NC, 1988, 1991. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "The Genealogical Journal" - Randolph County, NC, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Genealogy Correspondence - United Kingdom. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Genealogy Correspondence - United States. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Genealogy Material - United Kingdom. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Genealogy Material - United States. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Green, Colleen Blaylock. (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- "History of John Simpson Blaylock Family" by Linda Luffman Blaylock. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Morgan-Blair-Kersey-White-Blaylock. (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
- Obituaries. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Photographs. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Research Notes. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Research Notes. (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- Springfield Church (High Point, NC). (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Walker, Nathan. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- "The World Book of Blaylocks". (Box 3, Folder 6)
- "Blalock and Related Families: Pioneers in Virginia, the Carolinas, Alabama, and Texas, 1597-1988" by Delton D. Blalock. (Box 4)
- "The Blaylock Family: A Summary Concerning Some of the Descendants of Martin Blaylock (1793-1871)" - Microfilm Copy (Filmed by Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints in 1982). (Box 4)
- "Genealogy of the White and Kersey Families of the Counties of Randolph and Guilford, North Carolina" - Compiled by Luther A. White.. (Box 4)
- "Kinpatch: A Genealogy of Thomas and Brownfield Families" by Melva Ruth Thomas Campbell, 1980. (Box 4)
- Oak Ridge Military Academy Alumni Directory, 2000. (Box 4)
- Photograph - Bureau of Weights and Measures 19th Annual Conference, White House Reception, Washington, DC, 28 May 1926. (Box 4)
- "The Blalock's and Related Families" by Myreline Dailey Bowman, 1977. (Box 5)
- "Blaylocks of the American Frontier" - 2 copies (Published by Halbert's Family Heritage), 1998. (Box 5)
- "Blaylocks of the Civil War" (Published by Halbert's Family Heritage), 1999. (Box 5)